Guide to the Chambers Baird Papers, 1817-1933
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Chambers Baird papers 1817-1933
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Baird, Chambers, 1811-1886.
4 Linear Feet 2,255 Items
Lawyer and businessman, of Ripley, Ohio.
Correspondence and legal and financial papers, relating to Baird's law practice, his activities as paymaster of the U. S. Army (1863-1866) and as claim agent for soldiers' bounties and pensions (1863-1881); together with the papers of his son, Chambers Baird (b. 1860). Includes references to Ohio politics and business conditions during the antebellum period.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Chambers Baird Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1964-1965.
Biographical Note
Chambers Baird was a lawyer and businessman, of Ripley, Ohio.
Collection Overview
Correspondence and legal and financial papers, relating to Baird's law practice, his activities as paymaster of the U. S. Army (1863-1866) and as claim agent for soldiers' bounties and pensions (1863-1881); together with the papers of his son, Chambers Baird (b. 1860). Includes references to Ohio politics and business conditions during the antebellum period.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
United States. Army -- Pay, allowances, etc
Lawyers -- Ohio
Ohio -- Politics and government -- 1787-1865
United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Claims
Contents of Collection
- Chambers Baird Papers, 1817-1933, (8 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1821-1856, (6 folders) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1857-1864, June, (5 folders) (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1864, July-1866, May, (6 folders) (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1866, June-1875, (5 folders) (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1876-1895, (7 folders) (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1896-1933 and undated, (8 folders) (Box 6)
  - Legal Papers, 1817-1920 and undated, (7 folders) (Box 7)
  - Financial Papers, 1840-1919 and undated, (6 folders) (Box 8)
  - Printed Material, 1860-1897 and undated, (2 folders) (Box 8)
    Clippings, flyers, and circulars, 1872-1883; copies of items detached from collection to be cataloged as broadsides or pamphlets, 1860-1897 and undated.
  - Miscellany and Handwritten Notes (Box 8)